遙かな暗闇の奥深く潜む
Lurking deeply in the remote darkness
全てに疎まれたもの達の姿がある
are the figures of those shunned by all
上より来る釣瓶落とし
Coming from above, the well bucket falls
首を守ること
Watch your head
病は土蜘蛛の業
Pestilence is the spider's work
触れること能わず
You cannot make contact
橋姫に惑うならば
If you're troubled about the bridge princess
酒宴に忘れよ
forget it drinking
怪力乱神語らずに
Speaking not of the supernatural,
その気を引かぬ様
be sure not to draw her attention
かくも恐ろしき世に
In such a fearsome world
彼女らは何をも恐れずに
the girls fear not a thing
その足跡を糧とする
Feeding off how far they've come
人はそうして在るのだ
that's how people live
かくて生き延びる術の限り
Like this, the limits of the ways survival
明日に伝え残さん
they impart, leaving to tomorrow
畏れよ　しかし　呑まるること勿れ
Be afraid, yes, but you mustn't be consumed
我らが明日の為に
for the sake of our tomorrow
遙かな暗闇の奥深く潜む
Lurking deeply in the remote darkness
全てに疎まれたもの達の姿がある
are the figures of those shunned by all
隠し立ての出来ぬものには
For those who you can't hide secrets from
堂々とするべし
you must be dignified
火車に付き纏われたら
When followed by the corpse stealing cat
御命大事に
take great care of your life
謎多き地獄鴉
For the hell crow of much mystery
求む追跡調査
a follow-up check is wanted
似て非なるサトリの影
The shadows of a somehow different Satori
触れぬ神に何とやら
How shall you deal with an untouchable God?
共に畏れ　共に学べ
Be afraid together, study together
人はかくあるべし
That is how people should be
常に暗闇を照らすは
Constantly shining upon the darklness
栄智の光なり
is the light of wisdom
「正体見たり枯れ尾花」
“Look closely, and it's more ordinary than seems”
幻想に迷わず
hesitating not in fantasy
正しき知を記すこと
Scribing righteous knowledge
これを縁起とす
Take this as an omen
かくも恐ろしき世に
In such a fearsome world
我らも歩みを留めずに
neither do we stop walking
その足跡を糧とする
Feeding off how far they've come
人はそうして在るのだ
that's how people live
かくて生き延びる術の限り
Like this, the limits of the ways survival
明日に伝え残さん
they impart, leaving to tomorrow
畏れよ　しかし　呑まるること勿れ
Be afraid, yes, but you mustn't be consumed
我らが明日の為に
for the sake of our tomorrow
我ら幻と生きるものが
Us illusions, and living beings
末永くあることを
will exist forever, so
畏れよ　しかし　呑まるること勿れ
Be afraid, yes, but you mustn't be consumed
我らが明日の為に
for the sake of our tomorrow